# Saharsh Anand

# ABOUT

Software engineer with 5 years of full stack and DevOps expertise. Have rich knowledge and experience in Java, Spring Boot, REST, Python, Shell Scripting, Data Structure, Algorithm, Object Oriented Design, System Design and Product Building. Passionate about software and architecture design. Believe myself to be in an unending process of learning by continuously enhancing my knowledge and being a part of an organization that can provide me with opportunities and responsibilities to grow with it.

## SKILLS

Languages: Java, Python, Bash, JavaScript/TypeScript, NodeJS, HTML/CSS, C++

Operating System: Windows, Ubuntu, RHEL, UNIX

Technologies: Git/GitHub, JDBC, Gradle, Maven, Microservices, Kafka, Postman, Drools, Prometheus, Grafana,

Mockito, Docker, Kubernetes, ArgoCD, Tailwind, Webpack, Vite

Frameworks: Spring Boot, Spring Core, React, Angular, Vue, NextJS, Flask, Django, JUnit

Database: Mongo, PostgreSQL, Sybase, Firebase, Pocketbase

SRE: Gitlab Pipelines, Jenkins, Kubernetes, Bash

AI/ML: Llama, Mixtral, Orca, Ollama

Other: Reading, Long-form Writing, Public Speaking, Basketball, Badminton

## EXPERIENCE

#### Software Engineer (Associate), Goldman Sachs – Hyderabad

Sep 2021 – Present

- Working on building and delivering lending tools and applications for Goldman Sachs
- Responsible for collaborating with the business on the requirements and delivering the lending tool What-If Calculator as Technical Lead
- Enhanced several of Private Bank applications by migrating them away from legacy to state-of-the-art fully automated SDLC infrastructure
- Established SME of many Private Bank applications by reviewing and developing said systems

# Software Engineer, HSBC - Hyderabad

Jul 2019 – Sep 2021

- Developed the API solution for HSBC's instant lending application
- Enhanced the latency of the API by improving the decision engine loading strategy in Java
- Wrote a CLI-based application in Python to automate API data and performance testing for QA developers

#### Software Intern, Sophos Labs – Ahmedabad

Jan 2019 – Jun 2019

- Worked on a malware data management portal for lab researchers
- Built a dashboard to visualize the new malware and PUA identified
- Developed a request-based queue system to fetch the malware data from the firm's AWS Athena to reduce cost.

## EDUCATION

Nirma University

B. Tech – Information Technology

Kendriya Vidyalaya (CBSE HSC - XII)

Physics, Chemistry, Math and Computer Science

May 2015 Marks: 94.4%

May 2019

GPA: 8

#### Personal Projects

GitHub Reader | JS, HTML, Tailwind

github.com/5aharsh/github-reader

Read your favourite GithHb repos conveniently

Portfolio Site | JS, HTML/CSS

5aharsh.github.io

My portfolio site... through a terminal

Mesh | Python, JS, HTML/CSS

github.com/5aharsh/mesh

Think Windows Explorer, but inside a browser

Qmnt | PHP, JS, HTML/CSS

github.com/5aharsh/qmnt

Read your favourite GithHb repos conveniently